import { CATEGORY_MARVEL } from '../../constants/categories';
import type { Question } from '../../constants/questions';

export const marvelQuestions: Question[] = [
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: "What is Captain America's real name?",
        answers: ['Steve Rogers', 'Tony Stark', 'Bruce Banner', 'Clint Barton'],
        correctAnswer: 'Steve Rogers',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: "What metal is used to make Captain America's shield?",
        answers: ['Vibranium', 'Adamantium', 'Titanium', 'Steel'],
        correctAnswer: 'Vibranium',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'Who is the king of Wakanda?',
        answers: ['T’Challa', 'M’Baku', 'Rhodey', 'Nick Fury'],
        correctAnswer: 'T’Challa',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'What’s the name of Thor’s hammer?',
        answers: ['Mjolnir', 'Stormbreaker', 'Gungnir', 'Ragnarok'],
        correctAnswer: 'Mjolnir',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'What is the name of Peter Quill’s alter ego?',
        answers: ['Star-Lord', 'Nova', 'Iron Star', 'Galaxy Man'],
        correctAnswer: 'Star-Lord',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'Which Marvel character turns green when angry?',
        answers: ['The Hulk', 'Groot', 'Loki', 'Doctor Strange'],
        correctAnswer: 'The Hulk',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'What is the name of Tony Stark’s AI assistant?',
        answers: ['JARVIS', 'FRIDAY', 'KAREN', 'EDITH'],
        correctAnswer: 'JARVIS',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'Which movie introduced Spider-Man into the MCU?',
        answers: ['Captain America: Civil War', 'Spider-Man: Homecoming', 'Avengers: Age of Ultron', 'Iron Man 3'],
        correctAnswer: 'Captain America: Civil War',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'What species is Loki?',
        answers: ['Frost Giant', 'Asgardian', 'Eternal', 'Celestial'],
        correctAnswer: 'Frost Giant',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'Who is Scarlet Witch’s twin brother?',
        answers: ['Quicksilver', 'Vision', 'Hawkeye', 'Wiccan'],
        correctAnswer: 'Quicksilver',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'What is Black Panther’s real name?',
        answers: ['T’Challa', 'T’Chaka', 'Killmonger', 'M’Baku'],
        correctAnswer: 'T’Challa',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'Which character is NOT a member of the original Avengers in the first movie?',
        answers: ['Spider-Man', 'Iron Man', 'Thor', 'Black Widow'],
        correctAnswer: 'Spider-Man',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'Which Marvel character can manipulate time with the Eye of Agamotto?',
        answers: ['Doctor Strange', 'Wanda Maximoff', 'Thanos', 'Loki'],
        correctAnswer: 'Doctor Strange',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'Who said the line "I am inevitable"?',
        answers: ['Thanos', 'Ultron', 'Red Skull', 'Loki'],
        correctAnswer: 'Thanos',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'What is the name of the organization led by Nick Fury?',
        answers: ['S.H.I.E.L.D.', 'HYDRA', 'AIM', 'X-Force'],
        correctAnswer: 'S.H.I.E.L.D.',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'Who plays Natasha Romanoff (Black Widow) in the MCU?',
        answers: ['Scarlett Johansson', 'Brie Larson', 'Elizabeth Olsen', 'Natalie Portman'],
        correctAnswer: 'Scarlett Johansson',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'Which hero does Wanda Maximoff fall in love with?',
        answers: ['Vision', 'Hawkeye', 'Steve Rogers', 'Doctor Strange'],
        correctAnswer: 'Vision',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'Which multiverse-themed Marvel series stars Tom Hiddleston as the lead character?',
        answers: ['Loki', 'WandaVision', 'What If…?', 'Secret Invasion'],
        correctAnswer: 'Loki',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'Which character wears an armored suit and has a glowing arc reactor?',
        answers: ['Iron Man', 'War Machine', 'Ant-Man', 'Star-Lord'],
        correctAnswer: 'Iron Man',
    },
    {
        category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
        question: 'What item must the Avengers collect to reverse the snap in Endgame?',
        answers: ['Infinity Stones', 'Vibranium shards', 'Pym Particles', 'Dark Energy'],
        correctAnswer: 'Infinity Stones',
    },
    {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'What is the name of the planet where the Soul Stone was hidden in *Avengers: Infinity War*?',
    answers: ['Vormir', 'Xandar', 'Knowhere', 'Titan'],
    correctAnswer: 'Vormir',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'Which character is revealed to be a Skrull in the post-credit scene of *Spider-Man: Far From Home*?',
    answers: ['Nick Fury', 'Maria Hill', 'Talos', 'Both Nick Fury and Maria Hill'],
    correctAnswer: 'Both Nick Fury and Maria Hill',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'What is the name of the ancient being that created the Ten Rings in the *Shang-Chi* comics?',
    answers: ['Fin Fang Foom', 'The Mandarin', 'Xu Wenwu', 'Dormammu'],
    correctAnswer: 'Fin Fang Foom',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'In the MCU, which Eternal can control minds?',
    answers: ['Druig', 'Ikaris', 'Sersi', 'Sprite'],
    correctAnswer: 'Druig',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'Which Avenger does Peter Parker fight during his recruitment in *Captain America: Civil War*?',
    answers: ['Falcon', 'Black Panther', 'Winter Soldier', 'Scarlet Witch'],
    correctAnswer: 'Falcon',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'What alias does Natasha Romanoff use when hiding in *Iron Man 2*?',
    answers: ['Natalie Rushman', 'Emily Carter', 'Jessica Drew', 'Melina Vostokoff'],
    correctAnswer: 'Natalie Rushman',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'Who directed *Eternals* (2021)?',
    answers: ['Chloé Zhao', 'Taika Waititi', 'Ryan Coogler', 'Destin Daniel Cretton'],
    correctAnswer: 'Chloé Zhao',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'Which Marvel Disney+ show introduces the Darkhold book?',
    answers: ['WandaVision', 'Loki', 'Moon Knight', 'Ms. Marvel'],
    correctAnswer: 'WandaVision',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'What is the name of the dimension where Dormammu resides?',
    answers: ['The Dark Dimension', 'The Quantum Realm', 'The Mirror Dimension', 'The Void'],
    correctAnswer: 'The Dark Dimension',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'Which MCU film was the first to introduce Vibranium?',
    answers: ['Captain America: The First Avenger', 'Black Panther', 'Iron Man 2', 'Avengers: Age of Ultron'],
    correctAnswer: 'Captain America: The First Avenger',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'What name does Bucky Barnes go by while brainwashed?',
    answers: ['The Winter Soldier', 'White Wolf', 'Nomad', 'Ghost'],
    correctAnswer: 'The Winter Soldier',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'What year was the first Iron Man movie released?',
    answers: ['2008', '2010', '2006', '2009'],
    correctAnswer: '2008',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'Which Guardian of the Galaxy originally owned the ship "The Milano"?',
    answers: ['Peter Quill', 'Rocket', 'Yondu', 'Nebula'],
    correctAnswer: 'Peter Quill',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'In *Doctor Strange*, what relic chooses Stephen Strange?',
    answers: ['The Cloak of Levitation', 'Eye of Agamotto', 'The Staff of the Living Tribunal', 'The Book of Vishanti'],
    correctAnswer: 'The Cloak of Levitation',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'Which character says, "We are Groot"?',
    answers: ['Groot', 'Rocket', 'Peter Quill', 'Drax'],
    correctAnswer: 'Groot',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'Who is the main villain in *Ant-Man and the Wasp: Quantumania*?',
    answers: ['Kang the Conqueror', 'MODOK', 'Yellowjacket', 'Ghost'],
    correctAnswer: 'Kang the Conqueror',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'What is the real name of the Scarlet Witch?',
    answers: ['Wanda Maximoff', 'Natasha Romanoff', 'Agatha Harkness', 'Carol Danvers'],
    correctAnswer: 'Wanda Maximoff',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'Which organization was secretly operating within S.H.I.E.L.D.?',
    answers: ['HYDRA', 'AIM', 'The Ten Rings', 'The Hand'],
    correctAnswer: 'HYDRA',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'What is the name of the AI that replaces J.A.R.V.I.S. in *Avengers: Age of Ultron*?',
    answers: ['F.R.I.D.A.Y.', 'KAREN', 'EDITH', 'ECHO'],
    correctAnswer: 'F.R.I.D.A.Y.',
  },
  {
    category: CATEGORY_MARVEL,
    question: 'What MCU hero was previously a concert pianist before becoming a sorcerer?',
    answers: ['Doctor Strange', 'Wong', 'Kaecilius', 'Baron Mordo'],
    correctAnswer: 'Doctor Strange',
  },
];
